So the Problem Statement Worksheet is an approach that we use
to make sure that the definition of the problem is as good as it can be.
It starts with asking: what is the problem we're trying to solve?
And there we're applying the SMART framework to ensure
that definition is as clear and concise as possible,
and everybody's aligned on that definition.
It then has a number of other components, where
it asks us to consider: what is the context of the problem?
What is the scope of the solution set?
What are the constraints that we need to solve for?
Who are all the stakeholders we need to think through?
And ultimately, how are we going to measure
the success of solving this problem?
And the benefit of using the Problem Statement Worksheet
is that it's a great way
to drive alignment and ensure everyone is aligned
on what the problem we're trying to solve is,
and we've really nailed the definition of the problem.
So why do we use these components
in the Problem Statement Worksheet?
Well, it enables us to do a number of different things.
It enables us to think about how we can best align everyone on this problem —
both the people directly involved in the problem-solving process,
as well as the wider set of stakeholders.
It also enables us to be creative,
and to think around what all the options are that we should be considering,
and what is in scope,
and ensure that all the different sources of insight
are fully thought through from the beginning of the process.
And it also has an element of making sure we're practical.
And so as we think about what success looks like,
as we think about the constraints that we're facing,
it then enables us to be more precise
when we get to the structuring and prioritisation
steps of the hypothesis-led approach, to get there more efficiently.
So the Problem Statement Worksheet enables you
to both broaden the solution set —
and think about: have you thought about the full scope
and all the different stakeholders that need to be involved —
while at the same time ensuring that it's practical,
and you've thought about the different constraints you need to solve for
in order to deliver the impact and meet the criteria for success.